Today we have all been waiting to celebrate the birth of our Lord Jesus Christ.
Bu gün hepimiz Lordumuz Jesus Christ’in doğumunu  kutlamayı bekliyorduk.
There's so much significant that we are in a place here,
Jesus’ın doğduğuna benzer bir kulübenin bulunduğu
the same type of a hut Jesus had when He was born,
yerde olmamız çok anlamlı
and the wind was blowing from all sides
ve (o zaman) rüzgar her taraftan esiyordu
and it was difficult to keep the room very warm,
ve odayı çok sıcak tutmak zordu.
though if it is correct He was not born in the month of December,
Onun Aralık ayında doğmadığı doğruysa da,
in a warmer month, not so very cold, maybe this much as you see;
çok  soğuk olmayan, belki de şimdi gördüğünüz gibi, bu kadar soğuk olmayan,
so maybe that the climate of today is quite significant, with the climate
daha ılık bir ayda doğdu, yani belki de bu günkü hava bu yüzden oldukça anlamlı,
that He must have felt.
Onun hissetmiş olduğu iklimle birlikte.
As for you people, you don't feel any discomfort in this climate,
Onun için olduğu gibi, sizler de bu iklimde hiç rahatsızlık hissetmezsiniz,
nor in these surroundings nor in the Spartan living.
ne bu çevreden,  ne de Spartalı gibi yaşamaktan dolayı.
He never felt any discomfort, nor His Mother.
O asla herhangi bir rahatsızlık hissetmedi ne de Annesi hissetti.
When our attention is on our Spirit,
Dikkatimiz Ruhumuzda olduğunda,
then we do not feel the discomfort of nature or of worldly things.
dünyevi şeyler nedeni ile veya tabiat nedeni ile herhangi bir rahatsızlık hissetmeyiz.
This is the first sign when a Sahaja Yogi starts
Bu, bir Sahaja Yoginin konfor hakkında
complaining about comforts,
şikayet etmeye başlamasının ilk işaretidir,
then the first sign is that he is not a Sahaja Yogi as yet.
o zaman da bu onun, henüz bir Sahaja Yogi olmadığının ilk işaretidir.
To begin with you just get absolutely acclimatized with the climate and enjoy
Başlangıçta, önce  kesinlikle sadece iklime uyum sağlarsınız
the style, the speed, the way it is molding you.
ve onun tarzından, hızından, sizi soktuğu şekilden keyif alırsınız.
There's no friction between the nature and the body because the Spirit
Doğa ve beden arasında bir sürtüşme yoktur çünkü onları senkronize eden Ruh,
which is synchronizer, helps you to become one
sizin tabiat ile bir olmanıza yardım eder
with this nature and enjoy the best part of it.
ve bunun en iyi kısmından neşe duyun.
The way you are enjoying it shows that you are great Sahaja Yogis,
Bundan neşe duyma şekliniz, sizlerin büyük Sahaja Yogiler olduğunuzu gösterir
and that goes to My credit, I think,
ve bu Benim kredime yazılır, sanırım,
that you people have accepted all the discomfort as enjoyments.
hepiniz bütün bu konforsuzluğu, bir keyif olarak kabul ettiniz.
Christ coming was a great event as I have told you
Sizlere anlattığım gibi Agnya’yı oturtmak üzere İsa’nın gelişi,
to establish Agnya Chakra. And He was born on this Earth
büyük bir olaydı ve O bu dünyada  doğmuştu
but much before He was born in the consciousness
ama, Onun bilinçte doğmasından çok daha önce,
and that absolute consciousness itself took birth as Jesus Christ.
kendisi mutlak bilinçte  Jesus Christ olarak, (İsa olarak) doğdu.
To explain His life is only possible if you are Realized souls,
Onun yaşamını açıklamak ancak sizler Aydınlanmış Ruhlarsanız mümkündür
otherwise you cannot explain Christ - what He was, how He worked -
aksi halde İsa’yı izah edemezsiniz, O ne idi, nasıl çalıştı,
still it's very difficult to explain many things in Sahaja Yoga as you know,
bildiğiniz üzere  pek çok şeyi halen Sahaja Yoga’da da açıklamak çok zordur,
you just go on seeing things. Today you saw fountains
siz sadece bu şeyleri görmeye devam edersiniz.
coming out of the lake, which nobody can explain,
Bu gün hiç kimsenin açıklayamadığı, gölden çıkan pınarları gördünüz,
even the engineer said that they can't explain, nobody can explain it.
hatta mühendis bile bize, onların bunu açıklayamadıklarını söyledi.
It just happens that the water gets excited, feels the Divinity
Bu sadece meydana gelir, su heyecanlanır, Tanrısallığı hisseder
and starts pouring out its love in a bubbly manner.
ve kabarcıklar çıkartarak sevgisini akıtmaya başlar.
Can you imagine that even the water can feel it?
Düşünebiliyor musunuz, su bile bunu hissedebilir?
You have seen how the light can feel it, in the same way every element can feel it.
Işığın bunu nasıl hissedebildiğini gördünüz, aynı şekilde, her element bunu hissedebilir.
All those elements are within us, the highest of all,
Bütün bu elementler içimizdedir. Bunlar içinde,
as we say, is the light,
en yüksek olanı ışıktır
because light has an effect and that is governed by Jesus Christ.
çünkü ışığın bir etkisi vardır ve  ışık, Jesus Christ, İsa tarafından yönetilir.
Light has an effect, light shows things that are correct.
Işığın bir etkisi vardır, ışık doğru olan, hatasız olan şeyleri gösterir.
That's the one which makes us understand all the dimensions of worldly things
Bu, dünyevi şeylerin tüm boyutlarını anlamamızı sağlayan bir şeydir
and ultimately when this light comes from the Spirit and is enlightened by the Spirit,
ve nihayetinde bu ışık, kendisi ruhtan geldiği zaman ve ruh tarafından aydınlatıldığı zaman,
then you start seeing the other dimensions also which sometimes make you laugh,
bazen sizi güldüren, bazen gülümseten ve bazen de sizi ağlatan,
sometimes make you smile and sometimes make you cry also.
diğer boyutları da görmeye başlarsınız.
Such a beautiful new dimension you have achieved through Sahaja Yoga,
Sahaja Yoga sayesinde o kadar güzel yeni bir boyuta ulaştınız ki,
but it was all built in within you and you had to achieve it.
tüm bunlar sizin içinizde önceden bina edilmişti ve sizler, buna ulaşmalıydınız.
People on the other side had to work very hard,
Diğer tarafta olan insanlar çok çalışmalıydılar.
like Jesus Christ was born in a small manger to show
İsa’nın küçük bir yemlik içinde doğması,
that Divinity need not be born in royal families,
Tanrısallığın kraliyet aileleri içinde doğmaya ihtiyacı olmadığını göstermek içindi.
can be born in a manger,
O bir yemliğin içinde de doğabilir,
can be born anywhere, makes no difference to the Divinity.
her yerde doğabilir, Tanrısallık için bu fark etmez.
But that has given some funny ideas to people, that they are saying
Ama bu durum,  insanlara kimi tuhaf fikirler verdi ve onlar,
we should make ourselves miserable
kendimizi sefil bir hale getirmemiz gerektiğini söylüyorlar
and we should give away everything to God. God doesn't want anything.
ve  her şeyi Tanrıya vermeliyiz. Oysa Tanrı hiç bir şey istemez.
He cannot have anything, and you cannot give anything.
O, hiç bir şeye sahip olamaz ve siz Ona hiç bir şey veremezsiniz.
Is a wrong idea that you become like a pauper and give everything to God.
Yoksullaşmanız ve her şeyi Tanrıya vermeniz gerektiği, yanlış bir düşüncedir.
He doesn't want that. What He wants that you have to be happy, joyous and enjoying.
O bunu istemez. O sizin mutlu, neşeli, keyifli olmanızı ister.
That's the main point.
Esas nokta budur.
Also if you give a little bit, very little bit to God,
Diğer taraftan, eğer Ona biraz verseniz, Tanrıya çok azıcık bile verseniz,
then He gives you hundred times more.
O size yüz kat fazlasını verir.
That's why you have to give a very wee bit to God.
İşte bu yüzden Tanrıya,  çok minnacık bir şey vermelisiniz
But you don't have to hang yourself by the trees
ama kurban edilmek istediğinizi kanıtlamak için,
to prove that you want to sacrifice.
kendinizi ağaçlara asmamalısınız.
Christ has done everything for you. That's the beauty of His life is
Her şeyi İsa sizin için yaptı. Onun yaşamının güzelliği budur,
that from the very beginning of His birth He has shown that He has enjoyed
yaşamının başlangıcından itibaren kendisinin, bizlerin adlandırması ile,
no material well-being, as we call it.
maddi olmayan esenlikten keyif aldığını gösterdi.
He has not enjoyed any worldly things as we know of
Bildiğimiz üzere, O  hiç bir dünyevi şeyden keyif almadı
but that just means that He has done that for us to see
ama bu, şu anlama geliyor ki, O dünyevi şeyler peşinde
that there is no need for us to hanker after worldly things -
koşmamıza gerek olmadığını görmemiz için bunu yaptı,
they will hanker after us. You don't have to worry about these things.
onlar bizim arkamızdan koşacaklardır. Bu şeyler için endişe etmenize gerek yoktur.
What you have to worry is the Spirit, the main thing.
Endişelenmeniz gereken şey Ruhtur, esas nokta budur.
All His life, which was very short I should say, He has been trying,
Demeliyim ki, O çok kısa olan tüm yaşamı boyunca, çabalıyordu.
He was very much interested in evaluating people
O insanları değerlendirme konusu ile çok ilgilendi,
because He didn't know what sort of things these human beings are.
çünkü insan oğullarının ne tür bir şey olduklarını bilmiyordu.
He was a foreigner for these human beings. So He tried to evaluate
O, bu insanlar için yabancıydı. Bu yüzden de, onları  değerlendirmeye çalıştı
and in that evaluation
ve bu değerlendirme sırasında,
He said many things which are very remarkable, and one has to understand.
dikkate şayan pek çok şey söyledi ve insan bunları anlamalıdır.
One of the things He said that don't throw your pearls before people
Onun söylediği şeylerden birisi, “sizi anlamak istemeyen
who do not want to understand you. For Sahaja Yogis it is important to understand
insanların önünde incilerini saçmayınız” dır.
that you should not talk about Sahaja Yoga to people who are anti-God.
Tanrıya karşı olan insanların önünde, Sahaja Yoga hakkında konuşmamanız gerektiğini anlamak
may be anyone, there is no need to convince them about Sahaja Yoga
her hangi bir kişi olabilir. Onları Sahaja Yoga hakkında ikna etmenize gerek yok
because they are not your relations.
çünkü sizin akrabanız değil onlar.
Many people have only this worry how to convince my husband
Pek çok insanda, kocamı nasıl ikna ederim
or how to convince my brother, there is no need at all for you to work it out,
veya kardeşimi nasıl ikna ederim şeklinde, sadece bu endişe var. Sizin bunu halletmenize gerek yoktur,
just give them up on this point.
onları sadece bu noktada bırakın.
The another thing He has told us which is very important, I think,
Onun bizlere söylediği sanırım çok önemli diğer bir nokta da,
that we must forgive.
affetmek zorunda olduğumuzdur.
He has given the greatest weapon that we must forgive.
Affetmek zorundayız diyerek, bizlere en büyük silahı verdi.
Now it's such a practical thing to forgive.
Affetmek, o kadar pratik bir şeydir ki.
If you just forgive, the person doesn't exist anymore
Eğer sadece affederseniz, bu kişi artık sizin için mevcut değildir
and the person doesn't trouble you anymore, nor is he in your attention,
ve bu kişi sizi artık rahatsız etmez, ne de dikkatinizdedir,
just to forgive is a simplest thing to do and the highest thing to do
sadece onu  affetmek yapılabilecek en kolay şeydir ve bu,
to get relief from worldly or mental tortures that we get.
sahip olduğumuz dünyevi ve akli işkencelerden kurtulmak için (uygulanabilecek) en yüksek şeydir.
His life has been a story of spirituality,
Onun yaşamı spiritüelliğin bir tarihi oldu,
going through all kinds of turmoils and tortures,
her tür işkence ve hengameden geçerek,
all types of troubles that the Spirit can go through,
Ruhun görebileceği her tür sıkıntıyı yaşayarak O,
to show that nobody can kill that Spirit,
Gita’da söylendiği gibi,  ruhu hiç kimsenin öldüremeyeceğini gösterdi:
as it’s said in the Gita: "Nainam chidanti shastrani, nainam dahati pavakah,
“Nainam chidanti shastrani, nainam dahati pavakah,
na chainam kledayantya apo, na shosayati marutah".
na chainam kledayantya apo, na shosayati marutah”
It cannot be killed, it's an eternal life
O, öldürülemez, o ebedi yaşamdır
and He tried to prove through His life the eternity,
ve İsa sonsuzluğu,  kendi yaşamı ile kanıtlamaya çalıştı,
from the beginning to the end He showed that Spirit is above matter,
başından sonuna dek, Ruhun maddenin üzerinde olduğunu,
that nothing can dominate Spirit.
hiç bir şeyin Ruha hükmedemeyeceğini gösterdi.
It's a very big thing He has done for us is to create
Onun bizler için yaptığı şey olan Ruhumuza karşı
such a big confidence in our Spirit.
böylesi büyük bir güven yaratmak, çok büyük bir şeydir.
He has proved it beyond doubt.
O, şüphenin ötesinde bunu kanıtladı.
I hope you people will understand and will not bother Me or bother yourself
Umarım anladınız ve Beni de kendinizi de,
with small petty things here and there, is nothing important.
orada buradaki küçük önemsiz şeylerle meşgul etmeyeceksiniz, önemli olan hiç bir şey yok.
Ask for bigger things, eternal things, valuable things.
Daha büyük şeyler isteyin, sonsuz şeyler, değerli şeyler isteyin.
and you are enjoying yourself here very much
Ben de çok mutluyum ve bu gün pek çok
and today we have declared so many marriages.
evlilik duyurduk. Bu kadar kısa bir sürede,
There have been so many events in this short time.
pek çok olay oldu.
So I would like to bless you all for this Christmas Eve
Bu Christmas Arifesinde hepinizi kutsamak istiyorum.
and I wish you all very happy Christmas and Happy New Year.
Hepinize çok mutlu bir Christmas ve mutlu bir yeni yıl diliyorum.